<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Fundament Research Institute News</title><link>https://fundament.institute</link><description>Latest news and blog posts from the Fundament Research Institute.</description><generator>Fundament Research Institute RSS Generator</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Fundament Research Institute</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 06:53:54</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fundament.institute/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Initial Endowment</title><link>https://fundament.institute/posts/initial-endowment</link><pubDate>2025-07-15T08:30:04Z</pubDate><guid>https://fundament.institute/posts/initial-endowment</guid><description>
Last year, NLnet worked with Fundament Software to create a prototype for Feather UI, an open-source graphical user interface. Moving forward, we have founded the Fundament Research Institute, a non-profit organization, to take over stewardship of Feather UI to ensure transparency and enshrine our dedication towards maintaining Feather as an open-source project for the public good, directed by donations from our community, free from undue corporate influence.

Our prototype also revealed problems with Alicorn, an experimental language being developed alongside Feather. We have run into a few thorny type theory problems, which have made it clear that more mathematical research is necessary before we can effectively integrate effects and coeffects with a dependently typed inference algorithm. This research should be done in the open, as a public good, and to that end, the Fundament Research Institute has also taken over the Alicorn project, and is now accepting donations to fund further research and development, all of which will be done transparently and released without patents or any other restrictions.

All assets have already been permanently transferred to the Fundament Research Institute, which is now accepting donations. We also have a discord server where you can leave feedback or ask about funding details.

</description></item></channel></rss>